<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Policy &amp; Subsidies on ev Blogs | Latest Electric Vehicle Trends, Reviews &amp; Guest Posts</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/government-policy--subsidies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Policy &amp; Subsidies on ev Blogs | Latest Electric Vehicle Trends, Reviews &amp; Guest Posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 02:55:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/government-policy--subsidies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Start Electric Vehicle Business in India: Franchise Models That Work in 2025 and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/ev-franchise-india-guide-start-ev-dealership-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 02:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/ev-franchise-india-guide-start-ev-dealership-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 class=&#34;wp-block-heading&#34; id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;India is steering into a transformative era of electric mobility. As the nation accelerates its transition to cleaner transportation, 2025 is shaping up to be a landmark year for entrepreneurs exploring EV franchise India opportunities. Whether it’s setting up an electric vehicle dealership, launching an EV charging station franchise, entering battery swapping in India, or selling electric scooters, the time has never been more favorable. The government’s ongoing FAME II and state-level incentives, combined with rising consumer awareness and declining battery prices, have created fertile ground for growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Vehicle Government Policy in India: Incentives, Schemes, and Business Support (2025 Guide)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/electric-vehicle-government-policy-in-india-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 13:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/electric-vehicle-government-policy-in-india-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s transition to electric mobility is not just about reducing carbon emissions — it’s a strategic move to curb fuel imports, improve air quality, and become a global leader in EV technology. To make this happen, the Government of India has rolled out several &lt;strong&gt;electric vehicle policies&lt;/strong&gt; that provide financial incentives, tax benefits, infrastructure support, and ease of doing business for EV manufacturers, fleet operators, charging companies, and startups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Electric Mobility Mission Plan (NEMMP) in India: Full Guide for EV Businesses, Startups, and Infrastructure Support (2025 Edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-for-national-electric-mobility-mission-plan-in-india-2025-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-for-national-electric-mobility-mission-plan-in-india-2025-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we talk about the future of mobility in India, one policy that laid the groundwork for the entire electric vehicle (EV) ecosystem is the National Electric Mobility Mission Plan, also known as NEMMP. Whether you’re an entrepreneur planning to enter the EV business, an investor looking into the clean-tech space, or simply curious about how the Indian government is supporting the electric vehicle revolution, this guide will help you understand everything about NEMMP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAME India Scheme Explained: How to Claim EV Subsidies, Benefits for Businesses, and Future Roadmap (2025 Guide)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-claim-ev-subsidies-benefits-using-fame-india-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-claim-ev-subsidies-benefits-using-fame-india-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The future of mobility is electric, and India is accelerating that shift with the help of one of its most important initiatives: the FAME India Scheme. If you’ve been hearing the term “FAME” a lot and wondering what it actually means or how it impacts the EV ecosystem, this guide is for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production Linked Incentive (PLI) Scheme for Electric Vehicle Sector in India: Complete Business Guide, Eligibility, and How to Apply (2025)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-production-linked-incentive-pli-scheme-for-electric-vehicle-sector-in-india-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-production-linked-incentive-pli-scheme-for-electric-vehicle-sector-in-india-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India is charging full speed into the electric vehicle (EV) era, and if there’s one government initiative that’s transforming the industry from the inside out, it’s the &lt;strong&gt;Production Linked Incentive (PLI) Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;. Designed to promote large-scale domestic manufacturing, this policy isn’t just about subsidies. It’s about building a self-reliant, export-ready EV ecosystem that can compete with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State-Wise EV Policies in India (2025): Full Guide to Subsidies, Charging Station Support, and How to Apply for Benefits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-for-benefits-of-state-wise-ev-policies-in-india-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 12:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/how-to-apply-for-benefits-of-state-wise-ev-policies-in-india-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s electric mobility journey is progressing quickly. While national schemes like FAME and PLI are making headlines, much of the real impact is happening at the &lt;strong&gt;state level&lt;/strong&gt; — where governments are introducing their own electric vehicle (EV) policies to accelerate local adoption and support infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EV Charging Infrastructure Guidelines by Ministry of Power (2025): Full Guide to Setting Up Chargers, Getting Benefits, and Applying for Connections</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/ev-charging-infrastructure-guidelines-by-ministry-of-power-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 11:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/ev-charging-infrastructure-guidelines-by-ministry-of-power-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As India accelerates toward its electric mobility goals, the availability of fast, accessible, and affordable charging infrastructure is no longer optional — it’s critical. Recognizing this, the &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Power (MoP)&lt;/strong&gt; has released detailed &lt;strong&gt;Charging Infrastructure Guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; to simplify the process of setting up EV charging stations and encourage widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E-Amrit Portal by NITI Aayog: Full Guide for EV Buyers, Businesses, Startups &amp; Charging Infra in India (2025)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/e-amrit-portal-by-niti-aayog-full-guide-for-ev-startups-charging-infra-in-india-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 11:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/government-policy-subsidies/e-amrit-portal-by-niti-aayog-full-guide-for-ev-startups-charging-infra-in-india-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-growing world of electric vehicles (EVs), India is making waves. But as this green shift accelerates, many people still have basic questions: “Which EV should I buy?”, “Where can I charge it?”, or “How do I start an EV business in India?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
