<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EV Battery on ev Blogs | Latest Electric Vehicle Trends, Reviews &amp; Guest Posts</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ev-battery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EV Battery on ev Blogs | Latest Electric Vehicle Trends, Reviews &amp; Guest Posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 02:15:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ev-battery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Blade Battery: The Breakthrough Technology Powering the Future of Electric Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/inside-the-blade-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 02:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/inside-the-blade-battery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When most people think about electric vehicles (EVs), the first things that come to mind are how far they can go on a single charge, how fast they accelerate, and how long they take to recharge. But behind every EV, powering all that performance, is the battery. And not all batteries are made equal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover the Different Types of EV Batteries Used in India</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/different-types-of-ev-batteries-used-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 01:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/different-types-of-ev-batteries-used-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you’re thinking of buying an electric car, or maybe you’re just curious about all the buzz around EVs, right? With fuel prices going up every other day and the government pushing for greener transport, electric vehicles are slowly becoming a popular choice among Indian families. But let’s be real—buying an EV is not the same as buying a petrol or diesel car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solid-State Battery: The Future of Electric Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/solid-state-battery-the-future-of-electric-vehicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 01:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/solid-state-battery-the-future-of-electric-vehicles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles (EVs) are becoming more popular in India. Many people are considering switching from petrol or diesel cars to electric cars. But one big question always comes up — &lt;strong&gt;how good is the battery?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LFP vs NMC Battery: A Complete Guide to Choosing the Best EV Battery for Indian Roads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/lfp-vs-nmc-batteries-in-india-which-ev-battery-is-better-for-range-safety-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 22:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ev-battery/lfp-vs-nmc-batteries-in-india-which-ev-battery-is-better-for-range-safety-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to buying an electric vehicle (EV) in India, most people look at price, range, brand, or features. But very few pay attention to something even more important—the &lt;strong&gt;type of battery&lt;/strong&gt; inside the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
